# Jeeva R

7200712356 · jeevasmart82@gmail.com · Website - Jeeva LinkedIn - Jeeva

#### IT SUPPORT ENGINEER

IT Support Engineer with 2 years 3 months of experience providing Level 1 support to users via phone, email, Slack,and portal. Expertise in troubleshooting user desktop setups and remaining calm in difficult situations. Currently employed at Vectra Automation, Inc., where I am responsible for providing all IT support to users, including troubleshooting, Level 1 support, and end-user help desk support. Through my current position, I have honed my skills in delivering end-user help desk support and have developed the ability to remain composed and effective in challenging situations.

## **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Active Directory
Remote Troubleshooting
Technical Support

Global Service Desk Azure AD End User Support Hardware Configuration IT Asset Management User Account Management

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Vectra Automation, Inc.

Apr 2022 - Present

#### **Information Technology Support Engineer**

Accomplishments:

- Managed and deployed corporate PCs/laptops: configured new hardware, performed backups, diagnosed and repaired issues.
- Analyzed, logged, tracked, and resolved user queries concerning User's Desktop setups.
- Monitoring and supporting the infra as well the remote devices in the network.
- Created SSL VPN users within the Fortigate Firewall, L1 Network troubleshooting.
- Maintained and managed G-Suite admin activities, including user email ID creation and monitoring.
- Configured IIS servers for hosting the Nuget server.
- Installed SSL certificates on IIS Servers to ensure secure web services.
- Monitored and provided support for machines accessibility through SSL VPN, TeamViewer or Anydesk.
- Implemented security measures by creating group policies(GPO) to restrict specific permissions on desktops and set folder permissions for users.
- Conducted general IT tasks: onboarded new hires, and diagnosed and repaired end-user devices.
- Performed and monitored remote server backups (Acronis Image Backup).
- Handled troubleshooting of Active Directory, DNS, and DHCP to maintain networking connectivity.
- Managed endpoint security using McAfee and Symantec Endpoint Protection.
- Maintained IT asset data: tracked serial numbers, software keys, and locations.
- Conducted comprehensive system troubleshooting, and documented system events.
- Efficiently coordinated with vendors to resolve vendor-specific issues.
- · Coordinated testing, upgrades, and configuration of system files and services.
- Demonstrated a strong knowledge of performance optimization for Windows laptops, including reconfiguration, maintenance, and upgrades.
- Providing extended support to end users and resolving the issues immediately.

## Freelancer - Desktop Support

Nov 2018 - Present

Accomplishments:

- 1. System Installation and Configuration:
- Installation of the operating system (OS) and driver updates.
- Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux/Mac OS environments.
- Windows OS installation, formatting, partitioning, configuration, and troubleshooting.
- 2. Hardware and Network Support:
  - Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
  - · ISP routers and switches configuration.
  - Installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of LAN.
- Network administration: Static IP and DHCP configuration.
- · Setting up and sharing network printers.
- · Troubleshooting and resolving client system issues.
- 3. Mobile Phones and Security:
  - · Unlocking and flashing of all mobile phones.
  - · Installing anti-virus software and removing viruses.

# **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

Linux Tutorial - Great Learning
Google Workspace Administration - LinkedIn
Windows 10 for IT Support - LinkedIn
MacOS Ventura - LinkedIn

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Kings Engineering College**

Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer science Engineering

#### **Arignar Anna Higher Secondary School**

Jun 2015 - May 2017

Higher Secondary School Certificate, Mathematics and Computer Science